<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gautam Ajay</title>
    <description>a platform to share</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 10:18:20 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 10:18:20 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brownies vs Brocolli</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Every product is either a brownie or a brocolli. The brownie caters to immediate gratification (feel good now, cure boredom, distract from pain). The brocolli is about the long term value (sacrifice now for compounded gains). The best way to sell brocolli is to pan fry it with salt and oil to make it more palateable. Salt and oil happen to be 2 key ingredients in brownies.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/browniesvsbrocolli</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/browniesvsbrocolli</guid>
        
        <category>words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>iDEA - DetoxOS</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;problem&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our smartphones are the most useful tool that has simplified our lives in so many ways. However, it has become a source of digital addiction. Over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/1224510/time-spent-per-day-on-smartphone-us/#:~:text=According%20to%20a%20survey%20conducted,average%20on%20their%20phone%20daily.&quot;&gt;half of Americans&lt;/a&gt; spend over 6+ hours on their phones. A steady drip of dopamine that dulls greater joys in life such as relationships, emotions and steady growth. How can we manifest a world that has a better relationship with smartphones?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;opportunity&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opportunity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iPhone is the undisputed category king in the smartphone industry.  Other big players are trying to compete with Apple within the same category rather than defining the next era of smartphones. They each have their own gimmick (better camera, processor, better for games etc) but the marginal improvements are not enough to win the game that Apple has been dominating. A true contender would need to redefine the game to create a strong market share away from Apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solution&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build an operating system that prioritizes digital wellbeing as the primary mission. Not as an add on feature. The current app limit function on iOS does little to deter a user from continuing a TikTok binge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/time_limit.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;time limit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;detoxos&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DetoxOS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only OS designed to be used less. Similar the Hinge’s slogan “designed to be deleted”. Hinge realizes that the app is a means to an end to something more meaningful - true relationships. They expect users to delete the app (and forego additional revenue) by valuing the user’s long term goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With DetoxOS, you can design your own friction and customize according to your usage. Users can work with a specialist to set a custom plan, identify patterns and sign up for proven expert curated frameworks to lower their phone usage over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All apps fall into one the quadrants below. How can we find a middle ground where we can continue using useful apps while not letting addictive apps control us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/quadrant.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;app usefulness quadrant&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great UX is frictionless. DetoxOS intentionally adds friction to prevent binging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of friction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Routine tasks: Solve stoplight puzzles, math problems, reading comprehension, multiple choice answers, watch a motivational clip etc for every 3 TikToks you watch beyond your daily allotment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Master device: Once the app limit has been reached, the app can only be unlocked from a desktop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accountability Buddy: Register a friend or family member to keep you honest. They can see your total hours spent on your phone each week and are notified when you go over the limit. If you want to continue binging content beyond your limit, you need to call/text your accountability buddy to extend the limit (social pressure). Once they approve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In each of these situations, the non-essential apps are still available in dire scenarios (highly unlikely). However, the added friction makes it unappealing to continue binging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are fighting companies that spend billions on UX R&amp;amp;D. Large companies make money when you spend more time on their apps so they have no incentive to help users moderate their usage. DetoxOS recognizes that our rational brain that prioritizes long term value is overpowered by our emotional brain that wants instant gratification. By creating a framework to slowly lower usage over time, users will get back time in the day to learn, grow and deepen their relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/DetoxOS</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/DetoxOS</guid>
        
        <category>words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to transform into a dog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations! Admitting that human existence is the fundamental flaw in an otherwise perfect system is the first step. You are now on the path to becoming a full fledged canine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are many benefits to converting into any animal, dogs are a great choice. You gain the benefits of living in luxury in heated homes and have access to on-demand kibble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we do not have the technology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own transformation has been rocky. I was brought into  shelter multiple times before I could prove that I was once a human so&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, enough bullshit. Here are the steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Step 1: Dissolve your ego&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is very easy. Simply let go of the sense of identity that is prevents you from being your most honest self. You will now be free to chase rabbits into the bush,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Step 2: Sniff everything with unabashed curiosity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As your start transitioning, your sense of smell will heighten and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Step 3: Remove your emotional filter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a human, you are likely holding back in every exchange with other. This one takes a bit getting used to so start slow. You can start with wagging your tail with fervor when excited. The intensity corresponds to how much you care about that person. Eventually you will have to transition to licking them in the face&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you meet your friends and loved ones, just lick them in the face. If they are still human, they might respond negatively but dont&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Step 4: Let go of stories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past is the past. Let go of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Step 5: Piss on every wall, fire hydrant and tree&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important that your neibhors know that this is your territory. Make sure to gulp plenty of water before leaving the house and conserve your urine to make it last around the block. If you’re single, this is guaranteed to attract women so dont forget this step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some success stories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is George. We worked togeather at Deloitte a few years ago on the mergers and acquisitions team. George had a terrible marriage and a lackluster career trajectory under horrible leadership. As soon as he transformed, his wife divorced him and adopted him as a legal guardian. He also quit his job and spends most of his time retrieving tennis balls and swimming in the lake by their home in Dallas. Life is good for George.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/george.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;george&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Rachel. Rachel developed crippling anxiety from an abusive childhood. This has left her scarred and has affected&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/transform-into-a-dog</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/transform-into-a-dog</guid>
        
        <category>words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meta</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are no affiliate links in this post. A small portion of your time will be wasted reading this post from which I draw an immense sense of satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In lieu of writing a post with any real substance, I am writing this one. In the reddit community they would call this a shitpost. According to &lt;strike&gt;Webster's dictionary&lt;/strike&gt; Wikipedia, &lt;em&gt;Shitposting is posting “aggressively, ironically, and of trollishly poor quality.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first post is always the most difficult. In the pursuit of the perfect first post, I have procrastinated publishing this blog for months. As much as I claim to not buy into stories, I still care about what others think but im putting aside my pursuit of perfetionism to just get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some things you could be doing instead of reading this post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FaceTime a close friend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a new close friend.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sudoku.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complain to yourself on how terrible quarantine is&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get caught up in the past and wish things were different&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drink 16 oz of water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch a clickbait YouTube video and regret the 5 minutes of your life you will never get back&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow along with this 10 minute guided QiGong routine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scroll through Instagram. Its a great tool to stay connected with your friends.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn to juggle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sit with the stillness of the current moment and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously….this post is just fluff. It puts less pressure on my first real post so in the grand scheme of things, it has a purpose…..just like you and me :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Meta</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Meta</guid>
        
        <category>words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>If I could have 1 thing in life</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you ask most people what they want in life, you might get myriad of responses. The drunk will want nothing more than a crunchwrap supreme. The naiive will want to win the powerball. The Lonely will want a family and will settle for a dog. Prisoners will want freedom. So on and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What all these answers have in common is an appeasement of the negative emotions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I want:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/burning-monk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burning monk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really want to feel my flesh burn away&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want the sense of stillness inside&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all create stories in our head and float away from the objective reality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-I-want-in-life</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-I-want-in-life</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pasta Sauce</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/tomato_sauce.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;I stole this from the googles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;1 large can of San Marzano tomatoes&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;1 small can of tomato paste&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Italian Seasoning&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Salt&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Brown Sugar&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Crush the tomatoes with your hands&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mix tomatoes with the tomato paste, sugar and seasonings&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Adjust salt to taste&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Simmer for 40 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pasta-sauce</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pasta-sauce</guid>
        
        <category>food</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Producing vs Consuming</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: There is no absolute right or wrong action. The truth is nobody knows anything and I’m simply inviting you to ask yourself&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/ProducingvsConsuming</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/ProducingvsConsuming</guid>
        
        <category>words</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
